# **Overview**

I am a developer who is passionate about semantics, ecstatic about user experiences, and wistful for the <bli>tag. My unique background of traditional computer science and graphic design enables me to solve visual problems with efficient code. I have over 4 years of experience in designing and developing responsive user interfaces for screens of any size. My objective is to work for a company that is excited about building highly usable, fast, responsive web applications.

# **Education**

## **Taylor University, Upland Indiana**

http://taylor.edu

August 2012 - May 2016 (expected)

B.S. Computer Science New Media Systems, 3.74/4.0 GPA

### **BMK Academy**

High School *May 2008 – May 2012* College Prep, 3.81/4.0 GPA

# **Skills**

## Languages

- HTML, CSS, Sass, LESS, JavaScript
- Angular.js, Node.js, jQuery
- PHP, Python, Ruby
- C, C++, Java

#### Tools

- Git, Subversion
- Grunt, NPM, Bower, Unix tools
- Adobe Creative Cloud (Photoshop, Illustrator, Edge, After Effects)

#### **Frameworks**

WordPress, Express, Django, Ruby on Rails

# **Experience**

#### **Sells Group**

http://sellsgroup.com, Upland, Indiana

Front-End Web Developer

2013 – present

- Responsible for front-end development on client marketing sites. Worked with team to execute project roadmaps.
- Created a new build pipeline to streamline the development process. Set up automatic production deployments.
- Built custom e-commerce platform on top of WordPress and Woocommerce. Developed transparent AJAX user cart functionality extending from custom API and Angular.js.

## **Floodlight Design**

http://floodlight.design, Elgin, Illinois

Web Developer 2011 – 2013

- In charge of front-end development. Converted static Photoshop designs into flexible layouts
- Performed cross browser testing and debugging
- Integrated static templates with WordPress and Joomla templating systems
- Developed JavaScript for site interactions and API integrations

#### **Highgate Creative**

http://highgate-creative.com, Wheaton, Illinois

Mobile Web Developer

2013 - 2014

- Advised on responsive design best practices. Developed and wrote documentation for an internal responsive web design framework.
- Developed several mobile themes for a custom content management system
- Crafted a jQuery mobile theme for use on a client marketing website